正如我刚才提到的，执行器是实际移动机器人关节的装置。
As I mentioned a moment ago, actuators are the devices that actually move the robot joints.
并且机器人通常使用许多不同类型的致动器。一个
And there are a number of different types of actuators in common use for robotics. A
执行器的良好定义是它是一种引起运动的装置，它可能导致
good definition of an actuator is it is a device that causes motion and it can cause
线性运动或旋转运动。在这里，我们有一个线性执行器和轴
linear motion or rotary motion. On the top here, we have a linear actuator and the shaft
该线性致动器沿着线向后和向前移动。更常见的形式
of that linear actuator moves backwards and forwards along a line. The more common form
电动机具有旋转输出。可以考虑执行器的输出
of electric motor has a rotary output. The output of an actuator could be considered
无论是速度还是力量。也就是说，对于特定输入，电动机可能采用
as either a speed or a force. That is, for a particular input, the motor might adopt
特定的速度或它可能在旋转壳体中施加特定的力或扭矩。
a particular speed or it might exert a particular force or torque in the rotational case.
有许多不同类型的执行器，它们的基础物理类型各不相同
There are many different types of actuators and they vary in the types of underlying physics
那用来引起运动。最常见的执行器类型是液压执行器
that’s used to cause the motion. The most common types of actuators are hydraulic which
使用压缩油引起运动，气动使用压缩空气引起运动，
use compressed oil to cause the motion, pneumatic which use compressed air to cause the motion,
和电动使用电流和磁铁引起运动。
and electric which use electric current and magnets to cause the motion.
液压执行器在重型机械中非常常见，例如在建筑和建筑中使用
Hydraulic actuators are very common in heavy machineries such as used in construction and
在采矿业。它们是非常紧凑的设备，能够产生非常紧凑的设备
in the mining industry. They are very compact devices that are capable of generating very
当我想要挖掘挖掘机的桶时，这是非常重要的
high forces and that’s important when I want to pull a bucket of an excavator through
地面或我想举起许多吨土和石头。
the ground or I want to lift up many, many tons of earth and stones.
液压执行器是您在此图中看到的圆柱形设备。近距离，你
The hydraulic actuators are the cylindrical devices you see in this image. Up close, you
可以看到一个带有一些软管的大圆筒和一个伸出一端的闪亮棒
can see a large cylinder with some hoses going to it and a shiny rod sticking out one end
向前和向后移动。液压执行器实际上是一种非常简单的装置。该
that moves backwards and forwards. A hydraulic actuator is really a very simple device. The
圆柱体有两个压缩油进入和离开的端口然后，有
cylindrical body has got two ports where compressed oil enters and leaves and then, there is the
移动部件，前后移动的杆，在机器上施加力
moving part, the rod which moves backwards and forwards and exerts a force on the machine
或环境。
or on the environment.
液压执行器的简单示意图看起来像这样。在底部，
A simple schematic of a hydraulic actuator looks something like this. Down the bottom,
我们有汽缸本身。在里面，有一个活塞连接到
we have the cylinder itself. Inside that, there is a piston which is attached to the
棒是做工作的一块。
rod which is the piece that does the work.
有一个阀门组件，来自泵的高压油进入阀门和油
There is a valve assembly and high-pressure oil from the pump enters the valve and oil
离开阀门并返回泵。液压执行器转换油压
leaves the valve and returns to the pump. The hydraulic actuator converts oil pressure
线性力。如果我向阀门施加正信号并且油流如图所示
to a linear force. If I apply a positive signal to the valve and oil flows as shown by the
黑色箭头，活塞向右移动。油进入气缸的左端口
black arrows, and the piston moves to the right. Oil enters the left port of the cylinder
它从气缸的右侧端口出来。
and it exits from the right hand port of the cylinder.
如果活塞的面积是A并且如果油的压力是P，那么的力就是
If the area of the piston is A and if the pressure of the oil is P, then the force of
活塞是PxA.而且由于油压很高，可以施加的力
the piston is P x A. And because the oil pressure is so high, the force that can be exerted
由液压执行器非常非常大。如果我对阀门施加负信号，那么
by a hydraulic actuator is very, very large. If I apply negative signal to the valve, then
油沿相反方向流动，活塞向左移动。如果我申请
the oil flows in the opposite direction and the piston moves to the left. If I apply a
零信号到阀门，然后所有的端口都被阻塞，这意味着没有油可以
zero signal to the valve, then all the ports are blocked and this means that no oil can
进入或离开液压缸。因为油实际上是不可压缩的，所以
enter or leave the hydraulic cylinder. Because the oil is virtually incompressible, this
意味着活塞有效锁定，不能向左或向右移动。
means that the piston is effectively locked and it can’t move left or right.
虽然线性液压执行器是目前最常见的，但也有旋转式
Although the linear hydraulic actuator is by far the most common, there are also rotary
这里示出的液压马达在驱动该履带的马达中。
hydraulic motors such are shown here in the motor which is driving this caterpillar track.
您可以将其视为油驱动涡轮或桨轮。
You can think of it essentially as an oil-driven turbine or paddle wheel.
液压执行器非常紧凑，可以施加很大的力。但为了
The hydraulic actuators are very compact and can exert a lot of force. But in order to
使用液压执行器，你需要很多其他套件。首先，你需要阀门
use a hydraulic actuator, you need a lot of other kit. First of all, you need valves to
控制油流的方向。你需要一台压缩机来供应高压油
control the direction of oil flow. You need a compressor to supply the high-pressure oil
对于大型系统，您需要一台冷却器在压缩后冷却油。
and for large systems, you need a chiller to cool the oil after it’s been compressed.
通常你会有一个容纳高压油的蓄能器，总是很糟糕
Often you will have an accumulator that holds high-pressure oil and there is always an awful
很多软管。早在1984年，我就参与了这种灵活制造的开发
lot of hoses. Way back in 1984, I was involved in developing this flexible manufacturing
除了许多其他设备外，它还包含两个机器人。有
cell and it contained two robots in addition to a lot of other equipment. There is the
电动Puma560机器人，我们在这个课程之前已经见过很多次了
electric Puma 560 robot that we’ve met a number of times before in this course and
在前景是这个非常大的液压动力辛辛那提米拉克龙T3机器人。
in the foreground is this very large hydraulically-powered Cincinnati Milacron T3 robot.
在当天，液压技术是唯一可用于制造机器人的技术
Back in the day, hydraulics was the only technology that could be used to create a robot that
能够举起非常大的有效载荷。从那时起，已经有了很大的改进
was able to lift very large payloads. Since then, there has been massive improvements
在电动机技术方面，几乎没有液压动力制造
in electric motor technology and there are virtually no hydraulically-powered manufacturing
机器人今天存在。
robots in existence today.
气动执行器与液压执行器有很多相似之处。在这里，我们看到了一个
Pneumatic actuators have a lot of similarity to hydraulic actuators. And here we see a
线性气动执行器。气动系统使用压缩而不是压缩油
linear pneumatic actuator. Instead of compressed oil, the pneumatic system uses compressed
空气。就像液压系统一样，你需要很多其他套件。你需要有阀门，
air. Just like the hydraulic system, you need a lot of other kit. You need to have valves,
你需要有压缩机，你需要有蓄能器，当然，你需要
you need to have compressors, you need to have accumulators and of course, you need
有很多软管。作为线性气动执行器的替代方案，它是可能的
to have an awful lot of hoses. As an alternative to the linear pneumatic actuator, it’s possible
创造一个人造肌肉。这些装置直接将气压转换为线性
to create an artificial muscle. These devices directly convert air pressure to a linear
力。没有活塞参与。
force. There’s no piston involved.
在这里，我们可以看到大量的人造肌肉通过肌腱连接到手指
And here we can see a large number of artificial muscles connected by tendons to the fingers
在这个机器人手上。
on this robotic hand.
人造肌肉包含柔性腔室或袋子。当空气被泵入
The artificial muscle contains a flexible chamber or bag. As air is pumped into the
腔室，腔室变宽，也变短。我们可以看到整体
chamber, the chamber gets wider and it also gets shorter. And we can see that the overall
随着充气，肌肉的长度减少了。这些人造的一个特征
length of the muscle has reduced as it is inflated. One characteristic of these artificial
肌肉就像我们自己的肌肉一样，它们只能拉动，它们无法推动。在
muscles just like our own muscles is that they can only pull, they can’t push. In
为了制造有效的驱动系统，我们将它们用于我们所谓的对抗性
order to make an effective actuation system, we use them in what we called antagonistic
对。你可以看到这里说明的。当我给一块肌肉加压时，它会变短
pairs. You can see that illustrated here. As I pressurize one muscle, it gets shorter
并且顶部的轮子向右旋转。当我减压肌肉并加压时
and the wheel at the top rotates to the right. As I depressurize that muscle and pressurize
另一块肌肉，它变得更短，顶部的轮子向左旋转。
the other muscle, it gets shorter and the wheel at the top rotates towards the left.
这些人造肌必须成对使用。
These artificial muscles have to be used in pairs.